ASIDA YAMBAY

Junior Java Developer

asiday.github.io

Couple of years ago I've set myself the goal to start my professional path in the Java world. I used the pandemic time to learn Java, its ecosystem and make a step forward in my career. The systematic and efficient preparation for "Oracle Java 8 Certification" gave me a good introduction to the language itself. Moreover, I got to know popular frameworks and technologies, such as *Hibernate*, *Spring* and *Docker*.



At the beginning of this year I've launched my private project "News Aggregator" with the main purpose to strengthen my theoretical knowledge with practical experience. My good knowledge in Java on the one hand, and on the other hand my experience in data analysis and Python, make me a good reinforcement in diverse IT projects. My social skills also speak for me: I am motivated and well organized, can work independently, but I am also an engaged team player.

Java Journey

Java Project

Feb 2022 - Current

Create a News Aggregator Service using Spring Boot, Spring Data, Git, Docker. It is an application that collects news from different sources

Java Certification

Nov 2021 - Jan 2022

Prepare for the exam "Oracle Certified Associate, Java SE 8". And become Java Certified Programmer

Discover Modern Java Development

Mar 2021 – Oct 2021

My roadmap goes through Java Fundamentals and Essentials and basics of Maven, JDBC, JPA, Hibernate, Spring / Spring Boot, unit testing, Mockito, logging and Docker

Skills

Java			_	_	—
Spring Core/ Boot	_	_	_	_	_
Hibernate	_	_	_	—	—
SQL	_	_	_	—	_
Python	_	_	_	_	—
Data Science		_	_	_	—

Experience

Corporate Analyst Programm @ First Data, Bad Homburg

July 2019 - Dec 2019

Development of a single-page applications prototype with search and book elements using the Angular framework

Data Analyst @ IQVIA, Frankfurt a.M.

May 2018 - May 2019

Tool development in Python for data analysis with Pandas and NumPY. Development of algorithms for the automated generation of reports from various sources using OpenPyXL. Implementation of KPI dashboards in the BI tools Tableau / Power BI

Maternity

Sept 2014 - April 2018

Working Student

@ Ernst&Young, Frankfurt a.M.

Apr 2014 – Aug 2014

Cluster data analysis using TIBCO Spotfire. Preparation of SQL queries (SQLServer 2012) to determine relevant sales data. Presentations for various bank customers in the field of data analysis

Master Thesis & Working Student @ Umesoft, Frankfurt a.M.

June 2013 - Mar 2014

Design and implementation of software for the transformation of heterogeneous data for a chemical company (Java, Swing, XML, ApachePOI)

Education

M.Sc.High Integrity Systems @ FH Frankfurt a.M.

Sep 2011 - Aug 2014

Focus: data analysis, distributed systems, realtime and simulation methods

Diploma in Informatics @ St.Petersburg State Uni

Sept 2004 - Aug 2010

Focus: analysis, algebra, programming, international relations

Languages

German (Test-DAF)	
English (IELTS)	
French	
Russian	
Tatar	

Soft Skills

#teamwork #flexibility
#willingnesstolearn #motivation
#analyticalthinking #responsible
#timemanagement #planning

Interests









Sport Books Travel Painting

My Project - News Aggregator

This application is my "pet project" with a main goal to learn modern Java Enterprise development. The idea of the application is to collect the news into a database on the one side and on the other side to make these collected announcements available for requesting by some REST service. Which is ready to be used as a backend for e.g some web or mobile application. This application and all the collected data are used only for the personal learning purposes and are not a subject for commercial use.

JAVA

Java is a platform of choice for this project because of solid environment, mature frameworks and big community which let newbies to start easier into development carreer

SPRING DATA

In this project, I decided to use the Spring Data on top of Hibernate to work with the persistence layer. My database of choice is MariaDB

GIT

The version control system of the project is Git. The source code is hosted on the GitHub and is publicly available under the link https://github.com/asiday/news-aggregator

SPRING BOOT

I build simple Spring Boot applications. Spring Boot makes it easier to configure my applications, to integrate it with the persistence layer and to create REST endpoints

DOCKER

I use Docker to create deployable applications. The Docker Compose helps me then to deploy my applications to my home server

WEB APPLICATION

In the future, this part is planned to be written using Angular Framework. I already have some expirience with this framework and plan to refresh my knowledge within this project





